azcardinals.com 2019-04-22

# Cardinals Official Team Website I Arizona Cardinals – AZCardinals.com

## **Arizona Cardinals Privacy Policy**

##### **Revised March 2019**

The Arizona Cardinals Football Club ("we," "our," "us") respects your privacy and values your trust and confidence. This privacy policy (the "Privacy Policy") applies to our website [www.azcardinals.com](http://www.azcardinals.com/) (the “Website”), mobile application, and online services that link to or post this Privacy Policy (collectively, the "Services"), and explains how we collect, use, and disclose information through the Services. By using the Services, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. Please note that this Privacy Policy does not apply to any information that is collected or obtained through applications, sites, or services that do not link to this Privacy Policy (including the Team Shop) or information collected by the NFL or the other NFL member clubs (the "Member Clubs") or NFL mobile applications.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

  1. **Information Collection**
  2. **How information** **May Be Collected**
  3. **Use of Information**
  4. **Sharing of Information**
  5. **Social Networking Services**
  6. **Links To Other Web Sites**
  7. **Security**
  8. **Children's Privacy**
  9. **Changes To This Privacy Policy**
  10. **Access/Choice/Retention**
  11. **Your California Privacy Rights**
  12. **International Users**
  13. **Contact Us**

**1\. Information Collection**

You generally are not required to provide information about yourself when you visit the Services. However, we may ask you for some or all of the following types of information when you register with our Services, sign up for contests or sweepstakes, use a send-to-a-friend feature, participate in surveys, access various content or features, submit comments or content, or directly contact us with questions or feedback:

  * Contact information, such as name, e-mail address, postal address, birthdate, and telephone number;
  * Unique identifiers, such as a user name or password;
  * Demographic information, such as gender;
  * Financial information, such as credit card or other payment information;
  * Geolocation information;
  * Communications preferences;
  * Search queries;
  * Comments and other information posted in our interactive online forums;
  * Correspondence and other information that you send to us; and
  * Additional information as otherwise described to you at the point of collection or pursuant to your consent.

We also may collect certain information automatically when you visit the Services, including:

  * Your Internet Protocol (IP) address, which is the number automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet and that can sometimes be used to derive your general geographic area;
  * Other unique identifiers, including mobile device identification numbers;
  * Your browser type and operating system;
  * Sites you visited before and after visiting the Services;
  * Pages you view and links you click on within the Services;
  * Information collected through cookies, web beacons, local shared objects, and other technologies;
  * Information about your interactions with e-mail messages, such as the links clicked on and whether the messages were received, opened, or forwarded; and
  * Standard Server Log Information.
  * Mobile Application: When you download and use our mobile app, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier (or "UDID"). We collect your location-based information for our marketing purposes based on your current location. You may opt-out of location-based services at any time by editing the setting at the device level.

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve our marketing and analytics.

 **2\. HOW INFORMATION MAY BE COLLECTED**

We may collect information from you in several different areas on the Website, including but not limited to those described below:

Registration: You may be asked to complete a registration form and provide personal information; you may also be asked to choose a user ID and password in order to take advantage of certain features the Website may choose to offer, such as newsletters or contests. Participation in registration is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website.

Newsletters and Website Emails: We offer free newsletters to share information with you about the Website, about us and our affiliates and subsidiaries, or about our marketing partners and advertisers and sponsors. You may receive a newsletter either by registering for a particular newsletter or in conjunction with a special feature or membership for which you have registered on the Website. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website. You may also cancel your free email subscription by following the instructions provided on the Website or in the newsletter or email. You can also e-mail the site at [Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net](mailto:Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net).

Contests or Sweepstakes: We periodically operate contests and sweepstakes through the Website that may require registration or the submission of personal information. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website. Your personal information may be used to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other related purposes (see the rules of each contest for details about how your personal information will be used). We may also ask your permission to allow us to publicly post some of your information on the Website, such as on a winner’s page, in the event you win a contest or sweepstakes. To request removal of your personal information from our winner’s page, contact us at [Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net](mailto:Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. Except as required by applicable law, we will not post your information without your permission. In some instances, a third-party advertiser or sponsor may operate or host a contest or sweepstakes on the Website and collect your information. In those cases, where we are not the operator or host of the contest or sweepstakes, we do not collect your information and we have no control over the information collected from you. Accordingly, we urge you to review the advertiser's or sponsor's privacy policy applicable to the contest or sweepstakes before participating.

Surveys or Voting: From time-to-time we may request personal information from you in conjunction with a survey or voting poll. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website.

Cookies, Beacons, and Tags: Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts are used by Arizona Cardinals and our partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. A cookie is a unique, random number that is stored in the browser on your computer. Cookies automatically identify your browser to the Website whenever your computer is used to visit the Website. Cookies also let us know how many people visit our Website and where visitors go on the site. In addition, cookies can let us know other information, like what web browser is being used to access the Website. For registered users, cookies can make using the Website easier for you by saving information such as your passwords or preferences. By tracking how and when you use the Website, cookies help us determine which areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to the Website are based on data obtained from cookies. Accepting cookies allows you, among other things, to personalize your experience on the Website. Cookies may also allow the Website to present to you advertising which may be of interest to you. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, your browser should contain an option that allows you to disable or delete cookie data at any time. Some areas of the Website, however, may not provide you with a personalized experience if you have disabled the use of cookies. The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, and tracking utility company is not covered by our privacy policy.

IP Addresses and Click-Stream Data: We may collect IP addresses and/or click-stream data. An IP address is a number associated with the service through which you access the Internet, like your ISP (Internet service provider), your company, or your university. At times, we also use IP addresses for purposes of system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers and sponsors, for example regarding the frequency with which our guests visit various parts of our sites. We may combine this information with personal information. Click-stream data is information collected by our computers when you request web pages from the Website. Click-stream data may include such information as the page served, the time, the source of the request, the type of browser making the request, the preceding page view and other such non-personal information. When analyzed, this data helps us analyze how visitors arrive at the Website, what type of content is most popular, what type of visitors in the aggregate are interested in particular kinds of content and advertising, and the like.

Social Media Widgets: Our Website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and other Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

Transaction Information: If you conduct a financial transaction with our Website, we will ask you to complete an order form that will request certain information from you, including contact information, demographic information and financial information. We will use this information to complete the transaction that you have requested, i.e., to deliver the information, products or other services that you order, and to invoice you. For your protection, such information is collected and stored through encrypted means.

 **3\. Use of Information**

  * We may use information that we collect through the Services for a variety of purposes, including to:
  * Provide you with the products, promotions, services, newsletters, and information you request and respond to correspondence that we receive from you;
  * Contact you via email and otherwise about your account, products, services, contests, and events that we think might be of interest to you;
  * Send you promotional material or special offers on our behalf or on behalf of our marketing partners and/or their respective affiliates and subsidiaries and other third parties.
  * Maintain or administer the Services, perform business analyses, or for other internal purposes to improve the quality of our business, the Services, and other products and services we offer;
  * Publish stories, comments, photos, and other information posted in our interactive online features;
  * Customize and personalize your use of the Services;
  * As otherwise described to you at the point of collection or pursuant to your consent; and
  * If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about season tickets, we will ask for your friend's name and email address to send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. We store your friend’s email address and name for the sole purpose of sending an email and tracking the success of any referral program we may administer. Your friend may contact us at [Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net](mailto:Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net) to request that we remove this information from our database.
  * Mobile Applications: We may send you push notifications from time-to-time in order to update you about any events or promotions that we may be running. If you no longer wish to receive these types of communications, you may turn them off at the device level. We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our mobile software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personal information you submit within the mobile application.

**4\. Sharing of Information**

We are committed to maintaining your trust, and we want you to understand when and with whom we may share the information we collect. We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement.

  * **Service Providers:** We may share your information with service providers that perform certain functions or services on our behalf (such as to host the Services, fulfill orders, provide products and services, manage databases, perform analyses, process credit card payments, provide customer service, or send communications for us).
  * **Subsidiaries and Affiliates:** We may share your information with all members of the NFL Family, including, without limitation, NFL Properties LLC, NFL International LLC, NFL Enterprises LLC, NFL Ventures, L.P., and NFL Ventures, Inc.
  * **Select Business Partners:** With your permission, we may share your information with select business partners so that they can provide you with special offers, promotional materials, and other materials that may be of interest to you. For example, you may be presented with an opportunity to have certain information shared with our third-party business partners when you enter a contest or sweepstakes or elect to receive marketing offers or other information. If you do not elect to have your information shared, it will not be shared with such third parties. We take measures to help ensure that our partners protect the confidentiality, integrity, and security of any information we share with them. However, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of our business partners, which may use your information for their own purposes.
  * **Third-Party Ad Serving and Audience and Traffic Measurement Services:** We may use third parties to serve advertisements on the Services. These third parties may set their own cookies or similar web technologies to collect information about users' online activities over time and across different websites. To manage your preferences you may opt out here: <http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/>.
  * **Business Transfer:** If we sell all or part of our business, or make a sale or transfer of assets, or are otherwise involved in a merger or business transfer, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy, a business reorganization, or similar event, we may transfer your information as part of such transaction.
  * **Administrative or Legal Process:** We may disclose your information to third parties in order to protect the legal rights, safety, and security of our organization, our corporate affiliates, subsidiaries, business partners, and the users of our Services; enforce our Terms of Use; respond to and resolve claims or complaints; prevent fraud or for risk management purposes; and comply with or respond to law enforcement or legal process or a request for cooperation by a government or other entity, whether or not legally required.
  * **Interactive Features:** We may share information with third parties when you post information to a user profile or a public area of the Services, such as a chat room, forum, blog, or other community tool. If you post to these interactive features, it will be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. We cannot ensure that parties who have access to such information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when using these features.
  * **Other Parties with Your Express or Implied Consent:** We may share information with third parties when you consent to such sharing. For example, if you win a contest or sweepstakes, we may ask your permission to publicly post certain information on the Services identifying you as the winner.
  * **Aggregate Information:** We may share aggregate information, such as demographic and usage statistics, with advertisers, sponsors, or other organizations.
  * **Geolocation:** We may share your geolocation data with third parties for the purpose of them serving you ads or marketing promotions based on your current location. If you wish to opt out of sharing your information in this manner please contact us at [Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net](mailto:Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net).

In addition, we may allow third parties to place and read their own cookies, web beacons, Local Shared Objects, and similar technologies to collect information through the Services. For example, our third-party service providers may use these technologies to collect information that helps us with traffic measurement, research, and analytics.

 **5\. Social Networking Services**

We have worked with certain third-party social media providers to offer you their social networking services through our Services. For example, you can use third-party social networking services, including but not limited to Facebook, Twitter, and others to share information about your experience on our Services with your friends and followers on those social networking services. These social networking services may be able to collect information about you, including your activity on our Services. These third-party social networking services also may notify your friends, both on our Services and on the social networking services themselves, that you are a user of our Services or about your use of our Services, in accordance with applicable law and their own privacy policies. If you choose to access or make use of third-party social networking services, we may receive information about you that you have made available to those social networking services, including information about your contacts on those social networking services.

You also may be able to link an account from a social networking service (e.g., Facebook, Twitter, Instagram) to an account through our Services. This may allow you to use your credentials from the other site or service to sign in to certain features on our Services. If you link your account from a third-party site or service, we may collect information from those third-party accounts, and any information that we collect will be governed by this Privacy Policy.

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

 **6\. Links to Other Web Sites**

The Services may contain links to other websites or online services that are operated and maintained by third parties and that are not under the control of or maintained by us. For example, if you "click" on a banner advertisement, the "click" may take you off the Website onto a different website. These other websites may send their own cookies to you, independently collect data or solicit personal information, and may or may not have their own published privacy policies. Such links do not constitute an endorsement by us of those other websites, the content displayed therein, or the persons or entities associated therewith. This Privacy Policy does not apply to such third-party content. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of any third-party websites or services.

 **7\. Security**

We have adopted security procedures and reasonable safeguards to help protect against loss, misuse, and unauthorized access to the information you provide to us. For example, if we collect financial information, we will use encryption software to help protect this information when it is in transit. Please note, however, that no data transmission or storage can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your information and privacy, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you disclose or transmit to the Services and cannot be responsible for the theft, destruction, or inadvertent disclosure of your information.

 **8\. Children's Privacy**

 **8A. Scope.**

We may collect personal information from users who are under the age of thirteen (13) through their use of the Services. To the extent that this type of personal information is collected, we do so in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (15 U.S.C. 6501 et seq.).

COPPA requires us to inform parents and legal guardians about how we collect, use, and disclose personal information from Website users under the age of 13. By using the Services, you agree to the terms of this section of our Privacy Policy (individually, the “Children’s Privacy Policy”).

This Children’s Privacy Policy incorporates by reference our Terms and Conditions, which can be viewed by using the following link: [<https://www.azcardinals.com/about-us/terms-conditions>].

As used in this Children’s Privacy Policy, the following terms have the following meanings:

“Parent” includes legal guardians.

“Child” or “Children” means a user or users that are under the age of 13.

“Personal Information” or “Profile Information” means individually identifiable information including personal information such as first and last name, birthdate, phone number, physical address, email address, shirt size, and other contact information collected through the Services or when a parent registers a Child for an account.

For more information about COPPA, use the following link:

 **8B. Parental Consent.**

We are required by COPPA to use reasonable efforts to ensure that, before we collect any Personal Information from a Child, the Child user’s parent receives notice of and consents to our information collection and disclosure practices. If a user is under age 13, we must have “verifiable parental consent” before we collect and use the Child user’s personal information. We accomplish this by requiring Parents to use a credit card when providing their Child’s Personal Information. Furthermore, Parents must acknowledge that they have read, understand, and agree to this Privacy Policy before we can collect their Child’s information.

 **8C. Information We Collect, How We Collect It, and Use of That Information**

Our Terms and Conditions and this Privacy Policy set forth the information that we collect from both Children and users who are over the age of 13. This information is collected in the same manner regardless of a user’s age.

Any information collected as part of the Arizona Cardinals Kids Club is only used for the purposes of delivering membership packages to the registered Child. This information is only collected with parental consent.

 **8D. How to Review, Delete, or Alter the Information Collected from Child Users.**

Parents can review their Child’s personal information at any time by contacting the Arizona Cardinals Box Office and requesting access to that information. Parents can also have their Child’s personal information deleted and refuse to permit further collection of such information by us.

If Parents wish to view, delete, or modify the information that we have collected about their Child, or if Parents want to delete their Child’s account or profile, Parents may do so by contacting the Arizona Cardinals Box Office directly, or by e-mailing to [Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net](mailto:Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net).

 **9\. Changes to This Privacy Policy**

We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. Your continued use of the Services after any modification to the Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of the new terms. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on the Services prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

 **10\. Access/Choice/Retention**

You may choose to receive promotional emails, newsletters, and similar communications from us. You may opt out of receiving commercial emails from us by clicking on the opt-out or "unsubscribe" link included in the commercial e-mails you receive. Please note that opt-out requests may take some time to be effective. Your opt-out request will not apply to messages that you request or that are not commercial in nature. For example, we may contact you concerning any purchases you have made with us, even if you opt out of receiving unsolicited commercial email messages.

If your information changes, or if you no longer desire to use the Services, you may request that we update or remove certain information by signing into your account and making the required changes, by emailing our Customer Support at [Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net](mailto:Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net), or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will try to respond to your request within 30 days.

If you no longer wish to allow us to track your geolocation information or further receive push notifications in the Mobile App, you may turn these off at the device level or email us at [Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net](mailto:Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net).

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

 **11\. Your California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net](mailto:Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net) or write us at:

Arizona Cardinals Football Club  
PO Box 888  
Phoenix, AZ 85001

In some cases, third parties may be able to collect information about a user's online activities over time and across different websites when he or she uses our Services.

Some web browsers may transmit "do-not-track" signals to the websites with which the user communicates. Because of differences in how web browsers incorporate and activate this feature, it is not always clear whether users intend for these signals to be transmitted, or whether they even are aware of them. Because there currently is no industry standard concerning what, if anything, websites should do when they receive such signals, we currently do not take action in response to these signals. If and when a final standard is established and accepted, we will reassess how to respond to these signals.

 **12\. International Users**

Please note that the Services are directed towards users who reside in the United States. By using the Services, you consent to the collection, storage, processing, and transfer of your information in and to the United States, or other countries and territories, pursuant to the laws of the United States. While some of these countries may not offer the same level of privacy protection as your own, we commit to uphold the privacy protections as explained in this Policy.

 **13\. Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the privacy practices of the Services, please contact us by email at [Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net](mailto:Privacy@cardinals.nfl.net) or by regular mail at:

Arizona Cardinals Football Club  
PO Box 888  
Phoenix, AZ 85001-0888
